Finding Aid for Carr family papers, 1861-1930
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Carr family papers 1861-1930
Carr family.
0.4 linear feet
85104 Aa 2; UAx
Carr-Stearns family of Whitehall, Muskegon County, Michigan, and Ypsilanti, Washtenaw County, Michigan; family correspondence, including Civil War materials.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The collection was the gift of Marvin S. Carr (donor no. 5802 )
No further additions to the papers are expected.
The collection is open to research.
Members of the Carr-Stearns family were residents of Whitehall in Muskegon County and Ypsilanti in Washtenaw County, Michigan. One family member, Ezra Stearns was a soldier in 1st Michigan Engineers and Mechanics regiment during the Civil War. Another, Marvin S. Carr, was a student at Michigan State Normal College, Ypsilanti. He later was a cadet at the U. S. School of Military Aeronautics in various locations in Illinois, Texas, and Michigan.
The collection includes letters, diaries, and a memoir of Ezra Stearns relating to his Civil War service. There are also letters and other miscellanea of Marvin S. Carr written while a student at Michigan State Normal College, Ypsilanti, and later as a cadet at the United States School of Military Aeronautics at Champaign, Ill., Dallas, Texas, and Mount Clemens, Michigan during World War I. The photographs in the collection are of the family farm, with some high school photographs made in Whitehall public schools.
Subjects:
United States. Army. Michigan Engineers and Mechanics Regiment, 1st (1861-1865).; United States--History--Civil War, 1861-1865.; Women--Michigan--Ypsilanti.; Women--Michigan--Whitehall.; Muskegon County (Mich.).; Voyages and travels.; Travelers.; United States. School of Military Aeronautics (Champaign, Ill.).; Washtenaw County (Mich.).; Whitehall (Mich.).; World War, 1914-1918.; Ypsilanti (Mich.).; Michigan State Normal College.
Subjects - Visual Materials:
Brick industry--Michigan--Whitehall.; Carr, Beatrice.; Carr family.; Carr, H. B.; Carr, Marvin Stearns.; Michigan State Normal College.; Farms--Michigan--Whitehall.; Interiors.; Modern Woodmen of America.; Olivet College.; Schools--Michigan--Whitehall.; Stearns, Ezra, 1836-1922.; Whitehall (Mich.)
Contributors:
Carr, Marvin S.; Stearns, Ezra, 1836-1922.; Stearns family.; Carr, Susan E.
Genre Terms:
Ambrotypes.; Cyanotypes.; Photographs.
- Ezra Stearns
  - Correspondence, 1864-1918, of Ezra Stearns (Box 1)
  - Memoir entitled, "Three Years Campaign of a Private Soldier..." lst Michigan Engineers and Mechanics, undated (Box 1)
    (12 p., fragmentary)
  - Diaries, 1861, 1862, and 1863 (Box 1)
  - Civil War Miscellanea (Box 1)
- Marvin S. Carr
  - Letters, October 1912-January 1913, written while student at Michigan State Normal College, Ypsilanti (Box 1)
  - Letters, June-September 1918, written while a cadet at the U.S. School of Military Aeronautics, Champaign, Ill. (Box 1)
  - Letters, September-November 1918, written while a cadet at the U.S. School of Military Aeronautics, Dallas, Texas and Mt. Clemens, Mich. (Selfridge Field) (Box 1)
  - U.S. School of Military Aeronautics Miscellanea (Box 1)
  - Correspondence, 1915-1965 (Box 1)
  - Student papers, 1909-1926 (Box 1)
  - Poems, 1903-1946 (Box 1)
- Other family and related
  - Correspondence of Susan E. Carr concerning automobile trip through Michigan, Oregon, Idaho, and California, ca. 1930 (Box 1)
  - Mileage notes, ca. 1930 (Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous family correspondence (Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous family papers (Box 1)
  - Genealogical material (Box 1)
- Photographs
  - Marvin Carr (Box 1)
  - H.B. Carr (Box 1)
  - Carr family in Whitehall (Mich.) public schools (Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 1)
  - Modern Woodmen of America (Box 1)
  - Ezra Stearns (Box 1)
    (see also ambrotype in UAx)
  - Stearns farm (Whitehall), 1898 (Box 1)